The time has come, the moment that you
have been waiting for. We finally have
knowledge graphs in our NAN rag
template. So many of you have been
asking me to add this, especially after
I cover knowledge graphs with graffiti
and Python previously on my channel. So,
here it is. In this video, I'll show you
how it all works and how you can get it
set up for yourself. We're going to get
a little bit hacky today. It's going to
be fun and it'll still be super
practical. Now, first of all, what do
knowledge graphs actually give us? Well,
to answer that question, I want to go
back to the fundamentals of rag for a
second and then show you how we can
layer on top knowledge graphs to take
our agents to the next level. And so
traditional rag, what we've been working
with in this template so far is using a
vector database like I've been using
Postgress with PG vector. This could be
a dedicated vector database like
Quadrant or Pine Cone. You'll be
familiar with these things if you've
been following along with my template.
And this works great. I mean, there's a
reason that I've been just using a
vector database throughout the entire
template as I've been building it on my
channel, which by the way, I have this
playlist I'll link below if you want to
really start with the basics and then
get to the point where we have the more
complex and powerful template that
you're looking at right now. So, we have
our rag pipeline. This is the
foundational piece where we take our
data from our source like Google Drive
and we chunk it up into the bite-sized
pieces for our agent to search and
digest. And that's what we store in our
vector database. And the main problem
that we have with vector databases here,
as great as they are, is they don't do a
good job storing relationships between
the different entities that we have in
our data. So when we just dump all of
our chunks in a database like this, it's
hard for the agent to find one chunk and
then see how it relates to other things
that are also stored in our knowledge
base. That is what a knowledge graph
gives us. And that's what you're looking
at right here. So I built up this
knowledge graph in the rag pipeline now
using an MCP server that I'll introduce
you to in a little bit here. This is the
key. It's just a single node that I've
added to the pipeline. Super simple. And
so we're building up our knowledge graph
at the exact same time that we're
building up our vector database. So
we're storing the information in both
places just represented in different
ways. Because think about people,
companies, products, all of these
entities we have in our data. They're
very related to each other. And so we
want to be able to store those
relationships and give our agent the
ability to actually navigate between
these different nodes as they're called
based on the relationships. And so we
can look at a company and then we can
from there go and search and find the
executive leadership team as an example.
This is just demo data. But as our data
really starts to evolve and we have
thousands of entities and thousands of
relationships, agents definitely get
lost in the sauce trying to search
through these things in a vector
database. That's why we want a knowledge
graph. And so like I said, same data
that is being stored just represented in
different ways. And this definitely goes
with the theme of a gentic rag that I've
been covering when in this template.
We're giving the agent the ability to
search through our knowledge base in
different ways. So if we're asking about
a single company, well, we should
probably just go to the vector database
like we have been. But if we're asking
about how two companies work together,
now that would be a good example to go
and search the knowledge graph. All
right, let me actually show you this in
action now. And so I'll be explicit here
just for demo purposes to use the vector
database asking it to give me an
overview of a company that I have mock
data for in my Google Drive. And so,
yep, there we go. It uses the tool to
search the vector database. These are
the chunks it returned to give me the
answer. And there is our overview. All
right, looking good. So, yeah, in a
brand new conversation, let's try
something else. Let's say, tell me about
Dr. Tanaka and Dr. Chen. And I'll say
use the knowledge graph. Again, just
being explicit here because this is a
more relational question asking about
two entities at the same time. And take
a look at that. It is using the graffiti
MCP server which I'll show you how to
set up next to query our knowledge
graph. So the agent drops itself in here
finds the right nodes even looking
through relationships. It's really cool
the things that happen under the hood to
get us our answer. And I was being
explicit here but generally in your
system prompt for your agent this is
where you specify when is it optimal to
search the knowledge graph versus the
vector database. You can really play
around with this and tweak it to your
specific use case. I mean, that's the
big thing with this template, right, is
that it's all you take this and evolve
it to what works best for your use case
and your data for rag. So, there we go.
That's a quick demo. Now, let's get into
actually setting this up. And getting
knowledge graphs added into our template
here is super straightforward. There's
literally only two nodes that we are
adding on top of the previous version of
the template. We have one to insert into
our knowledge graph using the graffiti
MCP server and then one to give a tool
to our agent to search the knowledge
graph again with the graffiti MCP
server. And so most of the setup is
actually for the graffiti MCP. So that's
what I'm going to walk you through. Then
we'll cover these two nodes and exactly
how they work. Now this does assume that
you are using a self-hosted N8N. That is
a requirement for following along here.
the lang chain code node that I covered
in my last video on this template
require self-hosted N8N and this MCP
server needs to be run internally
alongside your N8N instance. So
obviously the cloud version would not
work. I'm going to be showing you how to
go into your machine where you're
hosting N8N bring graffiti and Neo4j
alongside it. So we have this MCP server
ready to be connected to. And so I will
be assuming that you already have
something like a digital ocean droplet
with N8N up and running. So if you don't
have that yet, just follow this guide
that I'll link to in the description to
get your own N8N instance self-hosted on
Digital Ocean. Digital Ocean's not
sponsoring this video. It's actually
just what I use to host my N8N. So
definitely follow along with that. Once
you have N8N up and running, that's when
we can dive into the instructions for
Graffiti. And so with a single docker
compose we're going to have the graffiti
mcp server and neo-4j which is our
underlying database hosted and then
we'll hook into it with nn. Now let me
be super clear. Neo4j is the database
like postgress where we store our
knowledge graph and graffiti is the
library. It's the tooling that gives us
the ability to extract from raw text the
entities and relationships to then store
in Neo4j and it gives us the MCP server
that makes it possible to use graffiti
with nan. Otherwise, this would be 100
times harder. And graffiti is the same
tool that I use with knowledger graphs
in Python that I covered on my channel
earlier. And so I've got my digital
ocean droplet up here. And this is the
same droplet where I have my N8N
instance up and running. And so I'm
going to follow these instructions,
which I'll also have linked in the
description to get graffiti in Neo4j up
and running. It's really not that bad
once we get to it here. So I'll go ahead
and copy this first command here to
clone the repository. So we're calling
in graffiti just like you do with N8N.
And then I'll change my directory to
graffiti/mcp_server.
And the first thing that we have to do
is set up our environment variables. So
I'll go into.example. I'll print it out
here so that you can see. The main thing
that we have to set is our OpenAI API
key because we're using a large language
model to extract those entities and
relationships. That's one of the things
that Graffiti does for us using OpenAI.
And you can configure this to use other
providers as well. That's outside of the
scope of this video, but definitely let
me know if you want me to evolve this
template to work with CloudN, different
LLM providers. There's so many things I
can do to continue to build this out for
you. So yeah, we just have to set our
API key and you can also change your
model name. And so what you want to do
is do a copy of.ample
and you want to change this to env. So
then we can do a nano.env.
And this is where we can go and set our
API key. So you change this value right
here. You can also change your Neo4j
password if you want for the underlying
database. And then to exit out of this,
you do control or command X and then Y
and then enter. Once you've made a
change, that's how you actually do it.
So here I'll actually make a change and
show you. So it's controll X, then Y,
then enter. That is how you save your
changes. So off camera, I'll set my
OpenAI API key and then I'll be back.
Oh, and one last note for this, you're
probably going to want to change your
URL from localhost to Neo4j. Since we're
working in containers here, we need to
reference the service name of our Neo4j
container. So just a tiny detail there
that's really important. That actually
tripped me up as I was getting this set
up for you. So, make sure you adjust
that. All right. Once you have your
environment variables set up, you can
run the pseudo docker compose up-d
command. This is going to get our
servers up and running. It might take
you a little bit longer. I already run
this in the background just so it's
quicker. And then to check the logs to
make sure things are actually good, we
can docker logs and then the name of our
server here. So, I'm just going to copy
this and paste it in. And then I this
should be uh pseudo as well. So, there
we go. All right. So, it's going to spit
out a ton of information. You can ignore
a lot of these warnings that you'll
typically see with graffiti. The main
thing that you're looking for at the
bottom here is that it says that ubicorn
is running on http 0000 port 8000. And
you can also configure this port if you
want as well by going into the docker
compose. It's a little bit of an
advanced thing, but I actually did this
because where I've been running this
before uh I was already using port 8000.
So I just changed this to map uh port
8030 to 8000 as well. So yeah, you can
go ahead and change that. Otherwise, we
are looking good. You now have
everything up and running. And you can
do a final check by doing uh docker ps-
a. It'll show you all of your containers
that are running. You want to make sure
that none of these say error or exited
or restarting, anything like that. So,
we've got our N8N and then caddy as
well. And then we got Neo4j and our
graffiti MCP. All right, things are
looking really good. Now, the last thing
that you need to do that is a kind of
awkward hacky thing is we have to make
sure we actually open up the port so
that N8N can connect to our graffiti
MCP. And this is the most technical and
hacky part of our setup here, but I'll
have step-by-step instructions in the
description so you can copy and paste
some things that we're about to do here.
I'll make it as easy as possible. So,
first things first, we need to change
our directory into where we set up N8N
because what we need to do is make a
super small tweak to the Docker Compose.
I already made the change here and I'll
have this in the description for you to
copy. But, we have to add an extra host
so we can use host.doccker.in.
This is how we're going to within our
N8N workflow builder connect N8N to our
graffiti MCP. And I'll show you what
that looks like in a little bit as well.
So, you just have to add these two lines
right here. And then again it's control
or command X Y and enter to exit once
you've made that edit in nano. So there
you go. And then you do pseudo docker
compose up-d. It's the exact same
command that you use to start n for the
first time and what we used previously.
So you go ahead and use that. Then we
are good to go. Now there's just one
other thing that we have to do with our
firewall here. What we need to do right
now is access the end container and
figure out what the gateway IP address
is. I know that sounds really technical
but don't worry. All we have to do is
pseudo dockerexec-it
and then the name of our container that
we get from the ps command. And so I'm
just going to copy this one right here.
This is the name of our container. Paste
it in. And then it is /bin /sh. And so
this is going to get us within the
docker container for nadn. So any
commands that we execute now are within
this container. We want to do ip route
and then gp default. And you can copy
and paste this from the description as
well. So we get this IP address right
here. So you want to copy this. This is
absolutely crucial because now we're
going to exit out of the NN container
and we're going to do pseudo UFW allow
from and then we have this IP that we
just copied. So I actually didn't do
that yet. So I'll copy and then I will
paste and then to any port and then 8000
or whatever the port that you have set
up for your graffiti MCP. So like I
changed mine to 8030. Whatever you need
to do here, change it. And so the reason
that we're doing something so specific
here is we don't actually want to open
up this port to the entire public. If we
wanted to do that, we could just do
pseudo UFW allow and then 8030. So
you're getting a little bit of a network
lesson here. I'll make it super brief, I
promise. But this would open up the
whole port to the entire internet. So
instead, we're only allowing this IP.
This is the gateway from the N container
to access this port. So, we're keeping
security super tight here. And then we
can do pseudo UFW reload. So, really
specific thing. Just have to bear with
me on that. But yeah, we have our
firewall set up. So, now N8N can access
the graffiti MCP and everything is still
secure in our digital ocean droplet. So,
now back in N8N, we are going to install
the community MCP node. And the reason
that we need this is pretty simple. The
MCP functionality built into N8N
natively only supports using MCP servers
as tools, but within our template, we're
using the Graffiti MCP server, not as an
agent tool. You can't actually set this
up with the native N8N integration with
MCP. So, we're going to use this server
right here. So, you can copy the name
N8N- nodes-mc.
Go to your settings in the bottom left
in N8N community nodes. And then when
you add a new node, you just paste in
the name that I copied from the mpm
page. And then you check this and
install. And then you are good to go.
And so I've got mine installed obviously
already. So if I add the plus icon here
and I search for MCP, take a look at
this. I can do MCP client. This is the
one from my community node. And the way
that you know that is that it has a
publisher here and it's via npm. And
specifically to test the connection with
the MCP server, I like to use the list
available tools function. And so I'll
bring in this node. I won't actually
attach it to anything yet. I'm just
going to set up my connection to my MCP
server, make sure everything's good, and
I can view the tools that are available
in the graffiti MCP server. And so I'll
make a brand new connection here just so
I can show you. So for graffiti, it is
server sent events as the protocol. And
then for the IP here, we did all that
work to set up host. docker.in internal
because we need to tell the nn container
to look outside of itself to our host
machine where we have the graffiti mcp
running and then my port is 8030 and you
can keep it as slash ssee. So go ahead
and click save and then we can exit out
of this and then we can execute this
step that's just in isolation right here
to make sure that things are working and
there we go. Cool. So we have an add
memory tool. This is what we have in our
rag pipeline for actually adding into
our knowledge graph. And then we have
the search memory nodes tool. This is
the primary one that I have as the tool
for my agent here in this template. And
then there are some other ones as well
that aren't really something I'm going
to be covering here, but it's actually
really nice. Like there are other tools
that we have here like get entity edge
that's more about like once you have a
certain node selected, you can then
search through relationships to find
other nodes around it. So, there's more
advanced things that I really do want to
cover later as well, but for this video,
I'm going to keep things simple and just
use the two tools that we have at the
top. I want to add memories and I want
to be able to search through memories.
And so, I'm going to delete this guy
right here cuz I'm just using that to
test the connection. The main thing that
I added into the rag pipeline here is a
single call to the graffiti MCP. And so,
my operation here is execute tool
instead of listing the tools that we
just looked at. And for the tool name
specifically, I actually got that by the
list operation. It is add memory. And
these are the two properties that we
have to specify. We need to specify the
name of the document that we're adding
in as an episode to graffiti. And then
also the episode body. This is the text
from the document that it is going to
use an LLM through OpenAI in this case
to extract the entities and
relationships. And so this single
edition is all we have to do. super
super clean to make it so that we're now
adding into our knowledge graph along
with our vector database in our rag
pipeline. And then it's just as easy for
the agent. So along with all the other
rag tools that we have, we're now just
adding a new MCP client tool where the
operation is again to execute a tool,
but this time the search memory nodes.
The only thing that we need to specify
for the parameters here is the query.
What's the query for searching our
knowledge graph? And we're letting the
LLM decide that. So the AI agent when it
invokes this tool, it determines what
the query is because obviously we don't
want to have to specify to the agent
exactly what the query needs to be. So
it gets to make that up. We're giving
the agent that control. And that is it.
That is everything you have to do. Like
I promised, the setup was mostly just
getting the MCP server up and running on
our digital ocean droplet. Yeah. And
then just for a little demo here, I will
do a test event with a file I have
updated in Google Drive. And then I'll
go ahead and send this in through the
full pipeline here. Take a look at that.
We have inserted it into our knowledge
graph. The full content of the file and
the title being sent in to be processed
into our knowledge graph. So an LLM is
going to run to extract the entities and
relationships. And there's a queuing
process here because knowledge graphs
are slower and more expensive compared
to a more traditional rag agent with
just a vector database. That's the last
point that I want to drive home for you
here. your use case might not be the
best for knowledge graphs if you don't
need that extra power for querying or if
you don't have really relational data.
Knowledge graphs might just slow you
down. Using an LLM to extract all of
these nodes can be a slow process. So if
you're working with a ton of data, you
should probably just stick to a vector
database. And I'll probably make more
content on the future doing these kinds
of comparisons for your use case,
helping you figure out do you want
knowledge graphs and vector databases or
just a vector database or just a
knowledge graph. There's so much more
that I could dive into here. Like I'm
really just scratching the surface of
what is possible with knowledge graphs
for you and helping you incorporate them
for the first time in your N8N
workflows. And so I hope that you found
this super super useful getting you
started with knowledge graphs in N8N. If
you did and you're looking forward to
more content on AI agents and rag and
knowledge graphs, I would really
appreciate a like and a subscribe.